Guide to the E. S. Reddy Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- United Nations
  - United Nations Periodicals and Pamphlets, undated (Box 43, Folder 1209 - 1213)
  - United Nations Radio, 1978-1991 (Box 43, Folder 1214-1215)
  - United Nations Staff Union, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 1216)
  - Women in the United Nations, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 1217)
  - World Health Organization (WHO), 1975-1991 (Box 43, Folder 1218)
- Miscellaneous, 1959-1984 (Box 44, Folder 1219-1222)
  - Additional material, 1984-1991 (Box 45, Folder 1223 - 1224)
- Buttons, undated (Box 45, Folder 1225)
- Audio tapes
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - World Conference for Sanctions Against South Africa, UNESCO, Paris, 1981 May (Box 46)
  - Meetings of Special Committee Against Apartheid, undated (Box 46)
  - Asian Regional Council for Action Against Apartheid, 1982 May (Box 46)
  - Meetings of the U. N. Security Council Committee on the arms embargo against South Africa, undated (Box 46)
  - Asian Regional Council for Action Against Apartheid, Manila, 1982 May 24-26 (Box 47)
  - Canon Collins, undated (Box 47)
  - Conference of West European Parliamentarians on Oil Embargo Against South Africa, A & P House, Brussels, 1981 January 30-31 (Box 47)
  - Heroes Day Meeting, United Nations, 1981 December 16 (Box 47)
  - International Seminar on Oil Embargo Against South Africa, Amsterdam, 1980 March 14-16 (Box 47)
  - Keynote Address by Chairman of Special Committee at 10thAnniversary of Organization of African Trade Union Unity, Addis Ababa, 1983 April 29 (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous Audio Tapes on Apartheid, undated (Box 47)
  - Opening Session of Conference of International Youth and Student Movement for the UN, Sigtuna, Sweden, 1980 May 24 (Box 47)
  - Press Conference by Chairman of Special Committee against Apartheid, UNESCO, Paris, 1982 March 3 (Box 47)
  - Press Conference, Jakarta, 1982 May 29 (Box 47)
  - Seminar on Nuclear Collaboration with South Africa, 1979 February 24 (Box 47)
- Newspapers, 1973-1990 (Box 48)
- Posters, undated (Box 49)
- Papers of IDAF for Southern Africa -London, 1982-1992 (Box 50)
- Correspondence files
  - Benson, Mary, 1967-1969 (Box 45, Folder 1232)
  - Breytenbach, Breyten, 1970 (Box 45, Folder 1233)
  - Davidson, Basil, 1974 (Box 45, Folder 1234)
  - Groenendijk, C., 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1235)
  - International Commission of Jurists, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 1236)
  - Naidoo, M. D., 1979-1980 (Box 45, Folder 1237)
  - Robinson, Randall, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 1238)
  - Turok, Ben, 1973-1974 (Box 45, Folder 1239)
  - American Broadcasting Company, 1983 (Box 53)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement (London), 1966-1977 (Box 53)
  - Asian Students Association, 1982 (Box 53)
  - Asmal, Kader, 1974 (Box 53)
  - Brutus, Dennis, 1970-1973 (Box 53)
  - General, 1964-1985 (Box 53)
  - Ginwala, Frene, 1971-1974 (Box 53)
  - Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights, 1970-1984 (Box 53)
  - Narasimhan, C. V., 1972 (Box 54)
  - Organization of African Unity, 1964-1981 (Box 54)
  - Permanent Mission of Nigeria to the UN, 1984 (Box 54)
  - South West Africa (Namibia), 1964-1991 (Box 54)
- Correspondence by organization, 1953-1980s
  - Africa Group of Sweden (AGIS) (Box 51)
  - African-American Labor Center (Box 51)
  - AMANDLA U. S. Tour Committee (Box 51)
  - Anti-Apartheid Bewegung (AAB) in der BRD und West Berlin (Box 51)
  - Black British Conference Against Apartheid Sport (Box 51)
  - Canadians Concerned about South Africa, Toronto (Box 51)
  - Citizens Association For Racial Equality, Inc., N. Z. (CARE) (Box 51)
  - Congress of the United States: Ad Hoc Monitoring Group on Southern Africa (Box 51)
  - East Tennessee Committee Against Racism and Apartheid (ETCARA) (Box 51)
  - Erklärung von Bern, Für solidarische Entwicklung (Box 51)
  - Greater London Council (Box 51)
  - HART: the New Zealand Anti-Apartheid Movement "Halt All Racist Tours" (Box 51)
  - Haslemere Group (Box 51)
  - Insurance Companies Campaign, New Zealand (Box 51)
  - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility (Box 51)
  - International Commission of Jurists (Box 51)
  - International Committee of Solidarity with the Struggle of Women in South Africa and Namibia (Box 51)
  - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) (Box 51)
  - International Film Festival Against Racism (Amiens), 1983 November 15-23 (Box 51)
  - Irish Anti-Apartheid Movement (Box 51)
  - KAIROS: Christians against Apartheid (Box 51)
  - Komitee Zuidelijk Afriks (Holland Committee on Southern Africa) (Box 51)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) (Box 51)
  - National Conference of Black Mayors, Inc. (Box 51)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in U. S. A. (Box 51)
  - Ruth First Memorial Trust (Box 51)
  - Second Brussels International Conference on Namibia, 1986 May 5-7 (Box 51)
  - South African Congress of Trade Unions (Box 51)
  - Southern Africa Solidarity Committee: University of Massachusetts (Box 51)
  - Sub-Committee on Racism, Racial Discrimination, Apartheid and Decolonization (NGO) (Box 51)
  - Swedish Athletic Association (Box 51)
  - Syracuse University (Box 51)
  - Task force on the Churches and Corporate Responsibility (Box 51)
  - United Nations Special Committee Against Apartheid (Box 51)
  - University of Brussels (Box 51)
  - Wales Anti-Apartheid Movement (Box 51)
  - Washington Office on Africa Educational Fund (Box 51)
  - African-American Women's Political Caucus (Box 55)
  - African Association of Political Science (Box 55)
  - African National Congress of South Africa (Box 55)
  - All African Convention (A. A. C.) and Unity Movement of South Africa (Box 55)
  - American Committee on Africa (Box 55)
  - Amnesty International (Box 55)
  - Anti Apartheid Movement for Freedom in Southern Africa (Box 55)
  - Apartheid Information Centre (Box 55)
  - Australian Mission to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Bermuda Workers' Socialist Party (Box 55)
  - Bishop Desmond Tutu (Box 55)
  - Books in Focus, Inc. (Box 55)
  - California Newsreel's Southern Africa Media Center (Box 55)
  - Center for International Policy (Box 55)
  - Committee on South African War Resistance (COSAWR) (Box 55)
  - Commonwealth Games Association of Canada Inc. (Box 55)
  - Conference in Solidarity with the Liberation Struggles of the Peoples of Southern Africa (Box 55)
  - CORSO: New Zealand Association for International Relief, Rehabilitation and Development (Box 55)
  - Counter Information Services (CIS) (Box 55)
  - Department of the Environment, London (Box 55)
  - Foreign and Commonwealth Office, London (Box 55)
  - House of Commons, London (Box 55)
  - INFORMAFRICA (Box 55)
  - Institute of Social Studies (Box 55)
  - Institute of Southern African Studies. The National University of Lesotho (Box 55)
  - International Atomic Energy Agency (Box 55)
  - International Campaign Against Racism in Sport (ICARIS) (Box 55)
  - International Conference of Experts for the Support of Victims of Colonialism and Apartheid in Southern Africa, 1973 April 9-14 (Box 55)
  - International Defence and Aid Fund for Southern Africa (IDAF) (Box 55)
  - International Maritime Organization (IMO) (Organization Maritime Internationale) (Box 55)
  - International University Exchange Fund (Box 55)
  - Iota Phi Lambda Sorority, Inc. Baychester, New York (Box 55)
  - Kathrada, Ahmad (Box 55)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law (Box 55)
  - Lewin, Hugh (Box 55)
  - Municipal Chamber of Sao Paulo Camara Municipal de Sao Paulo (Box 55)
  - National Anti-Apartheid Committee (Box 55)
  - New Zealand Defense and Aid Fund for Southern Africa (Box 55)
  - Office of His Highness the Sultan of Brunei (Box 55)
  - Office of the Associate Minister of Foreign Affairs, Wellington (Box 55)
  - Office of the Commonwealth Secretary-General, Marlborough House, Pall Mall, London (Box 55)
  - Pan Africanist Congress of Azania (Box 55)
  - Patrice Lumumba Coalition (Box 55)
  - People's Front for the Liberation of Southern Africa (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Barbados to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Brazil to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Canada to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Chile to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Ghana to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Iran to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of New Zealand to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Nicaragua to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Nigeria to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Thailand to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of the Federal Republic of Germany to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of the Kingdom of Lesotho to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of the Kingdom of the Netherlands to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Trinidad and Tobago to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent Mission of Zambia to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Permanent South African Mission to the United Nations (Box 55)
  - Republica de Venezuela (Box 55)
  - Rugby Football Union (Box 55)
  - Sameworld (Box 55)
  - Shipping Research Bureau (Box 55)
  - South African Military Refugee Aid Fund (SAMRAF) (Box 55)
  - South African National Olympic Committee (Box 55)
  - South African Non-Racial Olympic Committee (SAN-ROC) (Box 55)
  - South African Youth Revolutionary Council (SAYRCO) (Box 55)
  - South West Africa National United Front (Box 55)
  - Southern Africa Action Coalition (Box 55)
  - Southern African Students' Movement (SASM) (Box 55)
  - Soviet Afro-Asian Solidarity Committee (Box 55)
  - Union of Non-Independent African States (UNIAS) (Box 55)
  - United Nations (Box 55)
  - United Nations Centre Against Apartheid (Box 55)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) (Box 55)
  - United Nations Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR) (Box 55)
  - Unity in Action (Box 55)
  - University of Cape Town Students' Representative Council (Box 56)
  - University of Toronto (Box 56)
  - Uruguayan Association Against Racism and Apartheid (Box 56)
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth (Box 56)
  - Mouvement Contre le Racisme et pour l'Amitiéentre les Peuples (MRAP) [anti-apartheid poster exhibit, Paris] (Box 56)
  - Unsorted correspondence (two folders) (Box 56)
- Reports and writings
  - Documents of ACP/EEC Europe Parliament (Box 51)
  - "From Silence to Struggle: The Trajectory of Anti-Apartheid Struggle in Lenasia in the 1980s," by Transvaal Indian Congress Activists, undated (Box 51)
  - "Missions of Chairman of the United Nations Special Committee Against Apartheid to Nordic Countries, 1975-1982," notes on consultations compiled by E. S. Reddy (2 copies), 1985 June (Box 51)
  - Notes on visit of B. Akporode Clark, Chairman of the Special Committee Against Apartheid, to Federal Republic of Germany, 1980 June 8-14 (Box 51)
  - "Poetry" by Bojana Jordan, undated (Box 51)
  - "The Policy of Co-operation with the South African Regime in Uruguay," by the Uruguayan Association Against Racism and Apartheid, 1982 January (Box 51)
  - A paper addressed to a private meeting under chairmanship of Sir Robert Birley, House of Commons, 1970 March 12 (Box 51)
  - Meetings of Parliamentarians on oil embargo; letter of invitation, 1980 (Box 51)
  - Conferring of Honoris Causa Doctorate from the University of Carabobo, Venezuela, to Nelson Mandela, 1988 (Box 51)
  - New Zealand: apartheid in sport, 1976 (Box 51)
  - Solomon Mahlangu case, 1978 (Box 51)
  - Soviet and South African psychiatry letter by John Dommisse, M. D., 1982 (Box 51)
  - Statement following discussions between H. H. Francis, permanent representative of N. Z. to the U. N., and Leslie Harriman, undated (Box 51)
  - Summary of replies to questionnaire on action against apartheid by member parties of the Socialist International, undated (Box 51)
  - Text of letter from the office of Senator Edward Kennedy to State President P. W. Botha, 1985 February 20 (Box 51)
  - Organization of African Unity, 1971-1984 (Box 56)
  - Copy of letter to prime minister of South Africa, John Vorster, 1974 (Box 56)
  - The Cosmo Pieterse Case (Box 56)
  - Report of Mr. I. C. Mponzi, Organization of African Unity representative on the International University Exchange Fund (IUEF) Commission of Inquiry into the Activities of the South African spy, Craig Williamson, 1990 (Box 56)
  - United Nations Commission on Human Rights Working Group on Enforced and Involuntary Disappearances, undated (Box 56)
  - United Nations Commission on the Racial Situation in the Union of South Africa (background papers), 1953-1954 (Box 56)
  - United Nations Special Committee against Apartheid (originally in binders), 1977-1982; 56
    - Additional material, 1983-1984 (Box 57)
  - Wieschoff, Heinrich A. Director, Department of Political and Security Council Affairs, United Nations (Box 57)
- Additional material, 1976-1990; Accession 1993-M-092
  - Statements of Major General J. N. Garba, chairman of UN Special Committee Against Apartheid, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Additional material, 1913-1994; Accession 1994-M-029
  General note
  Also includes 1994-M-061
  - Correspondence/subject files
    - The Africa Fund, 1983-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - African National Congress, 1980-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Anti-Apartheid movement, London, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anti-Apartheid Organization of Trinidad and Tobago, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arms embargo against South Africa: letters from UN Special Committee against Apartheid to Security Council, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Black Sash, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bulletins, newsletters of various organizations, 1976-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Collins, John (Canon), 1967-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Gandhi, Mahatma: correspondence concerning Indians in South Africa, 1913-1941 (Box 1, Folder 9-13)
    - Huddleston, Trevor (Archbishop), 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - International Defence and Aid Fund for Southern Africa, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - International Olympic Committee (IOC), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Local Authority Action Against Apartheid": survey of UN Centre Against Apartheid, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - National and Olympic Sports Congress of South Africa (NOSC), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The Netherlands- South Africa: miscellaneous papers of the UN Special Committee Against Apartheid, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Non-Governmental Organization Committee on Human Rights (NGO) Subcommittee on South Africa, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Nordic Countries, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Organization of African Unity (OAU), 1977, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Pan Africanist Congress, 1981-1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Permanent Mission of New Zealand to the UN, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Permanent Mission of South Africa to the UN, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Permanent Mission of the Kingdom of Swaziland to the UN, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Printed material, 1982-1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Reeves, Ambrose (Bishop), 1974-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, New York Public Library, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Shipping Research Bureau: newsletters on the oil embargo against South Africa, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - South African Institute of Race Relations, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Southern Africa Education Program (SAEP), 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Special Committee Against Apartheid, UN, 1973-1991 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Special Committee on the Policies of Apartheid of the Government of the Republic of South Africa, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Tambo, Oliver: Speeches, Statements, 1964-1989 (Box 1, Folder 36-39)
    - United Nations related printed informational materials, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - World Federation of United Nations Associations (WFUNA): "Programme of Action against Apartheid and Colonialism in Southern Africa", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Writings
    - "America and Africa after Angola," Cas De Villiers, Focus, 1976 July (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "The Caribbean and Africa: A Geopolitical Analysis," by Linus A. Hoskins, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Disarmament, Development and Security: Towards a Safer and More Just World Order: A Mozambican Assessment, by Marcelino Dos Santós, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "Gandhi and his Significance": centenary conference papers, 1993 June 7-8 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - "Gandhi and South Africa," by E. S. Reddy, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "Japan's Nuclear Deals with South Africa," by Yoko Kitazawa, [1977?] (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "Notes on my visit to the USA, UK, Norway, Sweden, Denmark, and the FRG in connection with the issue of Apartheid in South Africa and Namibia," by Sat Paul Mittal, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - "South Africa's Destabilization Policy," by Hasu H. Patel, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Additional material, 1988-1994; Accession 1994-M-099
  - Inkatha Freedom Party; reports, statements, 1992 March-September (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "South Africa: Countdown to Elections": publication of the Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1993 December 3-1994 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Spotlight on Disinformation about Violence in South Africa": study by Anthea Jeffery, South African Institute of Race Relations, 1992 September (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Executive Secretariat of the Organization of African Unity to the United Nations: press releases, 1994 May 12-June 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Permanent Mission of South Africa to the United Nations: press releases, news highlights from the South African media, 1993 August 25-1994 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - United Nations Center Against Apartheid: "Chronology of Developments in South Africa", 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - UNICEF: press releases, 1994 June 9, 14 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Die Anti Apartheidskrant, 1994 March-April (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Additional material, 1968-1994; Accession 1995-M-032
  - Subject files, including scattered correspondence
    - The Africa Fund, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - African National Congress statements submitted to the Special Committee against Apartheid, 1963-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Die Anti Apartheidskrant, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes Jun-Jul and Oct-Nov issues.
    - Association of National Olympic Committees of Africa, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - British Defense and Aid Fund for Southern Africa, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fund for Democratic Elections in South Africa (FDESA), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Holiday greetings (ANC), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Huddleston, Trevor, fund raising for the Anti-Apartheid Movement, London, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights under Law, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - National Conference in Support of the African National Congress and Other Democratic Forces for a New South Africa, 1992 November 13-15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Conference was held in New York City.
    - National Manpower Commission (NMO), South Africa report on skilled laborers, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Non-Governmental Organizations (NGO) Committee on Southern Africa, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - People's Front for the Liberation of Southern Africa, Princeton University, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, New York Public Library, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - South African Information Exchange (SAIE); Institute of International Education (IIE), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Southern Africa Education Program, Stony Point, New York, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Southern African Non-Governmental Organization Network (SANGONet); Institute of International Education, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Tambo, Oliver, selected speeches, 1968-1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - United Nations
      - International Youth and Student Movement for United Nations (ISMUN), 1983 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Organization of African Unity to the United Nations, Executive Secretariat press releases, 1994 April-August (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Permanent Mission of Germany to the United Nations press releases, 1994 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Permanent Mission of South Africa to the United Nations news highlights, 1996 July-November (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Printed informational materials, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - UNESCO Office of Public Information press releases, 1994 August-November (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - UNICEF Division of Information press releases, 1994 September-November (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - UNITAR bulletins, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - United Nations radio broadcast typescripts pertaining to the British Anti-Apartheid Movement, 1984 June-August (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Washington Office of Africa (WOA), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Articles on South Africa - I, 1987-1993, by E. S. Reddy, Circa 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Additional material, Circa 1960-1991; Accession 1995-M-036
  Also includes Accession 1995-M-063
  - Memoirs of E. S. Reddy pertaining to Namibia, Nelson Mandela, United Nations and IDAF, Kaiser Matanzima, anti-apartheid movements, and colonialism, Circa 1960-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - United Nations Expert Group on South Africa, correspondence and memoranda received, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 1963-1991; Accession 1995-M-129
  - Speeches, interviews, and writings of Oliver Tambo during his time in exile, compiled by E. S. Reddy, 1963-1991 (Box 1)
    Presented to Nelson Mandela by K. R. Narayanan, Vice President of India, in New Delhi.
- Additional material, 1963-1995; Accession 1996-M-002
  - Correspondence, 1969-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Subject files of printed material
    - Action for Southern Africa (ACTSA), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Africa Fund, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - African National Congress (ANC), 1975, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Committee on Africa (ACOA), 1995 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amsterdam University Press, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Anti-Apartheid World Campaign, collection of photocopies of clippings from South African newspapers, 1993 March-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Association of West European Parliamentarians for Action Against Apartheid (AWEPAA) and Association of European Parliamentarians for South Africa (AWEPA), 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Call of Islam, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Community Elections '95, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Development Bank of Southern Africa, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Expert Group on South Africa
      - International Labour Office, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Memoranda and notes, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - UNESCO, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Habitat II, second United Nations Conference on Human Settlements, 1995 October (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hofstra Cultural Center, NY, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC), 1995 June (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)